<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on Michael Knapp&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on Michael Knapp&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Language</title>
      <link>/tech/javascript-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech/javascript-language/</guid>
      <description>output with console.log() semicolons are recommended but optional. comment syntax is normal // or /* */ Uses { } for code blocks. has &amp;ldquo;number&amp;rdquo; types, does not separate integers from floats.
So &amp;ldquo;//&amp;rdquo; is not integer division (Python), it is a comment. has &amp;ldquo;boolean&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;string&amp;rdquo;. No byte or rune type exists. has arrays. &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; is their catch-all dictionary and class type. double or single quotes can be used to define strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Languages</title>
      <link>/tech/languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech/languages/</guid>
      <description>This attempts to document languages not as how they work individually, but instead as how they deviate from a standard core programming language. It starts with the most common language features and functionality, and then shows how certain languages differ.
We should consider the following languagese: C, C++, java, javascript, python, typescript, golang, bash, Ruby, Rust
Operators  almost all languages have very similar operators. comparison: &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;, &amp;lt;=, &amp;gt;=, ==, !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe Scanned Documents</title>
      <link>/tech/transcribe-scanned-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech/transcribe-scanned-documents/</guid>
      <description>On Ubuntu, ImageMagick should be installed out of the box. Unfortunately it&amp;rsquo;s policy does not allow you to read PDFs by default.
First switch to sudo:
$ sudo su - Take a backup of the policy before editing it: cp /etc/ImageMagick-6/policy.xml /etc/ImageMagick-6/policy.xml.backup
edit the policy xml: $ /etc/ImageMagick-6/policy.xml
You should find a line like this: Replace it with this: You also need tesseract to be installed: $ apt-get install -y tesseract-ocr</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
